lan Del Giudice

SKILLS

Javascript – Native JS & ESNext. React & JS frameworks, Typescript. Also some nodeJS, Angular, Vercel and GraphQL. 12 years JS experience.

WordPress – Enterprise WordPress theme & plugin development, custom Gutenberg blocks, Headless WP & WP-JSON. 15 years PHP experience.

Styles – Organized, optimized and performant CSS. PostCSS & SCSS preprocessors, Webpack & npm.

HTML – Semantic, WCAG accessible markup. JSX/PHP/Liquid template components.

Design – Implementing Figma design mock-ups. Skilled with Illustrator, SVGs, and Photoshop.

Codebase Admin – Version control with Git. Code standards & review, testing, linters, and deployments.

Project Leadership – Technical architecture, project scope & estimate docs, team & client collaboration.

ABOUT

I'm a Brooklyn based full-stack web developer, originally from Providence, RI. A professional since 2009, I have 11 years experience working remotely at WordPress VIP partner agencies. I am passionate about front-end development, constantly learning and always excited for the next project.

EXPERIENCE

10up, Inc.

Senior Front-End Engineer, Feb 2023 - Nov 2023 Front-End Engineer, Feb 2019 - Feb 2023

Led project development teams at a fully-distributed WordPress VIP agency. Regularly working with React, TypeScript, NextJS, Gutenberg blocks, Headless WP, and WP plugins & themes. We delivered high quality, fully custom web applications with tight timelines & budgets, and contributed to project tooling.

Alley Interactive

UX Developer, Dec 2014 - Jun 2018

Collaborated with a remote scrum/agile team to build and maintain enterprise-scale themes & plugins for a WordPress VIP partner agency. As a project tech lead, we utilized CSS Preprocessors, ES6, Webpack, React, Angular, and rapid in-browser prototyping.

Oomph, Inc.

Front-End Developer, Jul 2012 - Feb 2014

Worked with different project teams at a WordPress VIP partner agency. Tasks involved custom theme & plugin development for WordPress and Drupal sites.

eMagine Communications

Website Maintenance, Mar 2010 - Mar 2012

Responsible for servicing client requests for website updates, improvements, and providing support for WordPress, Joomla, and .NET projects.

EDUCATION

Rhode Island College

Graphic Communications, Jan 2008 – Jan 2010
Pursued a BA in Graphic Communications. Course work included graphic design, prepress layouts & graphics, web development, and media literacy.